Amory Austin Collection Relating to Heraldry
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Amory Austin Collection Relating to Heraldry 1865-1917
MSS11346
Austin, Amory
1,500 items 3 containers plus 2 oversize 1.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collector. Notes, notebooks, and other papers relating to heraldry.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Austin, Amory.; Austin, Ivers James, 1808-1889.
Subjects
Heraldry.
Occupations
Collectors.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The Amory Austin Collection Relating to Heraldry was given to the Library of Congress by Catherine Austin in 1920.
Access and Restrictions
The Amory Austin Collection Relating to Heraldry is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Amory Austin was born to Ivers James Austin and Elizabeth Turner Amory Austin on July 24, 1849, in Boston, Massachusetts. He received a bachelor's degree from Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts, in 1871 and an S. B. from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, also in Cambridge, in 1873. He worked in analytical chemistry. In 1890, Austin was appointed expert compiler in the Statistical Division of the Department of Agriculture in Washington, D.C. He died on January 4, 1920, in Newport, Rhode Island.
Scope and Content Note
The Amory Austin Collection Relating to Heraldry spans the years circa 1865-1917 and consists of notes, notebooks, and other papers relating to heraldry collected by Austin. Included also is an obituary of Ivers James Austin, a Massachusetts politician, and a letter to him.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged by name of person or type of material.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm82011346
Container List
- Austin, Ivers James, letter and obituary, 1865, 1889 (Box 1)
- Notes on heraldy (Box 1)
  - Arms, crests, seals, and signals, drawn and printed, undated (Box 1)
  - Arms attributed to early Saxon and other kings, Apr. 1897 (Box 1)
  - Book of Public Arms, 1894 (Box 1)
  - Continental Sees, undated (Box 1)
  - Continental universities, undated (Box 1)
  - Emperors of the Holy Roman Empire, kings of Germany, and kings of Italy descended from Charlemagne, undated (Box 1)
  - England (Box 1)
    - Cambridge and Oxford, undated (Box 1)
    - Colleges of Cambridge, undated (Box 1)
    - Herald's College, undated (Box 1)
    - Hospitals and charitable institutions, undated (Box 1)
    - London livery companies, undated (Box 1)
    - Monastic houses in England and Wales, undated (Box 1)
    - Organizations of public interest, undated (Box 1)
    - Public and grammar schools in Wales, undated (Box 1)
    - Societies, undated (Box 1)
    - Towns and districts, undated (Box 1)
    - Universities, colleges, and technical schools, undated (Box 1)
    - Wives of sovereigns, undated (Box 1)
  - General orders for countries and towns, undated (Box 1)
  - Handbook of English Cathedrals, 1896 (Box 1)
  - "Heraldry," Encyclopedia Britannica, 1890 (Box 1)
  - India, undated (Box 1)
  - Italy: counts, kings, and dukes, undated (Box 1)
  - Robert I, King of the Scots (Robert the Bruce), 1897 (Box 2)
  - Russian crowns, undated (Box 2)
  - Societies, clubs, and other organizations, undated (Box 2)
  - United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, undated (Box 2)
  - Universal (encyclopedia), 1894 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, (4 folders) (Box 2)
- Heraldic listings, undated See Oversize, (2 vols.) (Box 3)
- Notebooks, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
- Printed matter, circa 1891-circa 1917 (Box 3)
- Oversize (Box OV 1-OV 2)
  - Heraldric listings, undated (Container 3), (2 vols.) (Box OV 1-OV 2)